stcu.org 2008-12-18

# STCU: Privacy Policy

#### STCU's Privacy Policy Notice

At Spokane Teachers Credit Union we respect the privacy of our members. We recognize the importance of maintaining the confidentiality of your personal financial information. This notice describes the privacy policy and practices followed by Spokane Teachers Credit Union. This notice explains what types of member information we collect and under what circumstances we may share it.

### Member Information We Collect

The Credit Union collects only relevant information about members that is needed to establish and maintain your account and services as the law allows or requires us to collect. We may collect personal and financial information about you (member information), which is "nonpublic." The member information we collect varies depending on the accounts and services you request and use. We collect information about you from the following sources:

### Application Information

We retain personal information we receive from you on any application you provide to us for membership, deposit accounts, EFT services, loans, financial planning, securities brokerage, insurance, or other Credit Union services. Examples of this information include: name, address, social security number, birth date, telephone number, employment and financial status, and credit history.

### Your Transactions

Any time you make a transaction on one of your accounts, including ATM, debit or credit card transactions, loan advances, transactions through STCU's NetTeller® Online Banking, over the phone with CATT® (our computer aided telephone teller) or at any branch, we retain the transaction information, including: your account number, the date, amount, location of the transaction, and other pertinent information.

### Credit Reports

When we evaluate your application for an account or service, we may request a credit report about you from a consumer reporting agency. We retain the personal and credit history information about you and we may use it to evaluate future account service requests.

### Online

We obtain information online when you visit our website, www.stcu.org. This includes retaining information you provide us on any online application, STCU's NetTeller® Online Banking transaction or information you send to us by e-mail.

### Member Information We Share

In order to provide financial services to you, we share certain information about you with our affiliates and third party service providers. However, we only share information to the extent necessary to service your account or offer new services to you. If we share your information, it is with the goal of bringing you quality services, more choices, and greater convenience. Information we may have about former members is generally only shared or disclosed if necessary to enforce or administer an account or as required by law.

### Sharing Information with Third Party Service Providers

In order for us to conduct our operations, including servicing your account or processing your transactions, we may need to share information with our service providers. Examples of these service providers include data processing companies, check, ATM and other payment processing companies, payment networks, loan service providers, collection agencies and credit reporting agencies. We may also share information with financial service providers with whom we have joint marketing agreements. Examples of these financial service providers include insurance companies, financial planners and security brokerage companies. These financial service providers act on our behalf and have agreed in writing to keep the member information we provide to them confidential. We share the following categories of information to third party service providers depending on the specific services provided:

  * Personal information (name, address, and account number)
  * Account information (type of accounts, account balances, and transaction history)
  * Transaction information (dates, amounts, locations, and type of transaction)

We do not sell member information nor share your account numbers with independent third party marketers offering their products and services. While we may assist in offering financial products and services of other financial service providers, we control the member information used to make such offers.

### Sharing Information as Legally Required or Permitted

We may share any member information of yours in response to a lawful request issued by a court, government agency, or regulatory authority or as permitted by law in order to administer or enforce your account. We may also share our experience information about you with credit bureaus. Our reporting to credit bureaus is governed by the Fair Credit Reporting Act, which affords you the right to make sure that your credit bureau reports are accurate.

### Our Confidentiality and Security Safeguards

We maintain strict policies and security controls to assure that member information in our computer systems and files is protected. Our employees are permitted access to member information that they may need to perform their jobs and to provide service to you. Our employees have access to such member information as necessary to conduct a transaction or respond to your inquiries. All employees are trained to respect member privacy. No one except our employees has regular access to the Credit Union computer system and records storage. The Credit Union has established internal security controls, including physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect the information you provide us and the information we collect about you. We will continue to review our internal security controls to safeguard your member information as we employ new technology in the future.

### Online Privacy Protections

At our website, www.stcu.org, you may apply for accounts and services and you may communicate with us via e-mail. To protect the information you provide us online, we use multiple levels of security. The application information we accept online through STCU's NetTeller® Online Banking service relies on industry standard "Secure Sockets Layer" (SSL) encryption to secure your transaction information and communication. This encryption standard may be updated from time to time as industry standards change. You are also protected against unauthorized online account access by at least two forms of authentication. STCU reserves the right to employ additional access restrictions for certain online transactions and services commensurate with the risk they represent. Generally, our e-mails are not secure. However, if we ask you to e-mail us information other than your name, address, e-mail address and phone number, it will be obtained using a secure (SSL encryption) e-mail form. When you visit our website, you can access site information, without revealing your personal identity. However, in order to help us identify you for future site visits, we use "cookies" to track your visit. A cookie is a piece of information that our web server stores on your computer hard drive and retrieves later to expedite your visit. The cookie will not request, require or collect personal identity information and you remain anonymous. Your member information is not accessed by or stored within a cookie in any way. We may link to other websites as a convenience to you. STCU does not warrant the content or service provided on those other sites, including the collection of member information. 

### Protecting Children's Information Privacy

Our online financial services are not designed for or directed toward children under the age of thirteen. We do not knowingly solicit or collect data from children and we do not knowingly market to children online. We recognize that protecting children's identities and online privacy is important and that responsibility rests with us and with parents.

### **Important Information About Procedures For Opening a New Account**

To help the government fight the funding of terrorism and money laundering activities, Federal law requires all financial institutions to obtain, verify, and record information that identifies each person who opens an account.

What this means for you: When you open an account, we will ask for your name, address, date of birth, and other information that will allow us to identify you. We may also ask to see, or request a copy of, your driver's license or other identifying documents.

### Privacy Pledge Inquiries

We reserve the right to change our Privacy Pledge in the future and will notify you of any changes as required by law. If you have any questions about our privacy practices, contact us by calling (509) 326-1954 or (800) 858-3750. You may also send us an e-mail at [info@stcu.org](mailto:info@stcu.org), or write to us at Spokane Teachers Credit Union, 1620 N. Signal Drive, Liberty Lake, WA 99019-9517.
